<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: network | just some lazy admins]]></title>
  <link href="http://lazyadmin.me/blog/categories/network/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lazyadmin.me/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-12T14:59:17+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://lazyadmin.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thang Pham & Kao Nhan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The day the routers die]]></title>
    <link href="http://lazyadmin.me/blog/2009/03/01/day-routers-die/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-01T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://lazyadmin.me/blog/2009/03/01/day-routers-die</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<embed flashvars="blogmode=1&amp;file=http://chacha.vn/embedded/v1.0/getMedia.php?songId=57690" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://chacha.vn/embedded/v1.0/mp3player.swf" wmode="transparent" allowscriptaccess="none" width="368" height="130"></embed><br />Bài hát khá thú vị của Gary Fieldman, nói về kết cục của IPv4 và sự cần thiết của IPv6.<br /><br /><span style="font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;">Lyrics:</span><br /><blockquote style="font-family: courier new;">a long long time ago<br />i can still remember<br />when my laptop could connect elsewhere<br /><br />   and i tell you all there was a day<br />the network card i threw away<br />had a purpose - and it worked for you and me…<br /><br />   but 18 years completely wasted<br />with each address we’ve aggregated<br />the tables overflowing<br />the traffic just stopped flowing…<br /><br />and now we’re bearing all the scars<br />and all my traceroutes showing stars…<br />the packets would travel faster in cars…<br />the day… the routers died…<br /><br /><span style="font-style: italic;">    Chorus (ALL!!!!!)</span><br /><br />   so bye bye, folks at RIPE 55<br />be persuaded to upgrade it or your network will die<br />IPv6 just makes me let out a sigh<br />but I s’pose we’d better give it a try<br />I suppose we’d better give it a try<br /><br />   now did you write an RFC<br />that dictated how we all should be<br />did we listen like we should that day<br /><br />now you back at RIPE fifty-four<br />where we heard the same things months before<br />and the people knew they’d have to change their ways…<br /><br />and we - knew that all the ISPs<br />could be - future proof for centuries<br /><br />but that was then not now<br />spent too much time playing WoW<br /><br />ooh there was time we sat on IRC<br />making jokes on how this day would be<br />now there’s no more use for TCP<br />the day the routers died…<br /><br /><span style="font-style: italic;">Chorus (chime in now)</span><br /><br />so bye bye, folks at RIPE 55<br />be persuaded to upgrade it or your network will die<br />IPv6 just makes me let out a sigh<br />but I s’pose we’d better give it a try<br />I suppose we’d better give it a try<br /><br />I remember those old days I mourn<br />sitting in my room, downloading porn<br />yeah that’s how it used to be…<br /><br />when the packets flowed from A to B<br />via routers that could talk IP<br />There was data… that could be exchanged between you and me…<br /><br />oh but - I could see you all ignore<br />the fact - we’d fill up IPv4<br /><br />but we all lost the nerve<br />and we got what we deserved!<br /><br />and while… we threw our network kit away<br />and wished we’d heard the things they say<br />put all our lives in disarray<br /><br />the day… the routers died…<br /><br /><span style="font-style: italic;">Chorus (those silent will be shot)</span><br /><br />so bye bye, folks at RIPE 55<br />be persuaded to upgrade it or your network will die<br />IPv6 just makes me let out a sigh<br />but I s’pose we’d better give it a try<br />I suppose we’d better give it a try<br /><br />saw a man with whom I used to peer<br />asked him to rescue my career<br />he just sighed and turned away…<br /><br />I went down to the net cafe<br />that I used to visit everyday<br />but the man there said I might as well just leave…<br /><br />and now we’ve all lost our purpose..<br />my cisco shares completely worthless…<br /><br />no future meetings for me<br />at the Hotel Krasnapolsky<br /><br />and the men that make us push and push<br />like Geoff Huston and Randy Bush<br />should’ve listened to what they told us…<br />The day… the routers… died<br /><br /><span style="font-style: italic;">Chorus (time to lose your voice)</span><br /><br />bye bye, folks at RIPE 55<br />be persuaded to upgrade it or your network will die<br />IPv6 just makes me let out a sigh<br />but I spose we’d better give it a try<br />I suppose we’d better give it a try</blockquote></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Anonymous</div>
<div class='content'>
Vui</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alice and Bob]]></title>
    <link href="http://lazyadmin.me/blog/2008/09/15/alice-and-bob/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-15T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://lazyadmin.me/blog/2008/09/15/alice-and-bob</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Alice và Bob là hai nhân vật thường xuyên xuất hiện trong các bài giảng và các vấn đề về mã hóa và bảo mật. Việc sử dụng hai cái tên này bắt nguồn từ việc các vấn đề mã hóa thường phải đề cập đến "A muốn gửi một thông điệp cho B". Ngoài Alice và Bob, còn có một số nhân vật khác như:<div>- Eve: người nghe trộm thông tin, được biết như là kẻ tấn công với hình thức passive.<br /></div><div>- Mallory: không như Eve, Mallory là kẻ tấn công  hiểm độc. Mallory luôn muốn sửa đổi thông tin, thay thế bằng tin khác hoặc nhân bản các tin lên,...</div><div>- Trend: may mắn cho Alice và Bob, họ luôn có sự giúp đỡ của Trend, bên thứ ba, người cung cấp các giao thức an toàn để truyền tin.<br /></div><div><br /></div><div>Bài hát sau do MC Plus+ (*) sáng tác. Bài hát nói về mối quan hệ của Alice, Bob, Trend, Eve và Mallory, cùng với các vấn đề liên quan đến an toàn mạng như các thuật toán mã hóa, ưu nhược điểm của chúng.</div><div><br /></div><div>[*] <a href="http://www.mcplusplus.com/">MC Plus+</a> tên thật là <a href="http://www.cs.purdue.edu/people/graduate_students/anavabi/">Armand Navabi,</a> đang nghiên cứu về khoa học máy tính tại đại học Purdue.</div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><embed flashvars="blogmode=1&amp;file=http://chacha.vn/embedded/v1.0/getMedia.php?songId=57694" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://chacha.vn/embedded/v1.0/mp3player.swf" wmode="transparent" allowscriptaccess="none" height="130" width="368"></embed><div>Lyric:</div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color: rgb(41, 48, 59);font-family:'Trebuchet MS';font-size:13;"  ><p style="margin: 0px 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 170%;"></p><blockquote><p style="margin: 0px 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 170%;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-style: italic;">Alice is sending her message to Bob<br />Protecting that transmission is Crypto’s job<br />Without the help of our good friend Trent,<br />It’s hard to get that secret message sent<br />Work tries to deposit the check of your salary<br />But with no crypto, it’ll be changed by Mallory<br />You think no one will see what it is, you believe?<br />But you should never forget, there’s always an Eve…</span></p><p style="margin: 0px 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 170%;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-style: italic;">[Chorus]<br />‘Cause I’m encrypting s**t like every single day<br />Sending data across the network in a safe way<br />Protecting messages to make my pay<br />If you hack me, you’re guilty under DMCA</span></p><p style="margin: 0px 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 170%;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-style: italic;">DES is wrong if you listen to NIST<br />Double DES ain’t no better man, that got dissed<br />Twofish for AES, that was Schneier’s wish<br />Like a shot from the key, Rijndael made the swish<br />But Blowfish is still the fastest in the land<br />And Bruce used his fame to make a few grand<br />Use ECB, and I’ll crack your ciphertext<br />Try CFB mode to keep everyone perplexed</span></p><p style="margin: 0px 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 170%;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-style: italic;">[Chorus]<br />‘Cause I’m encrypting s**t like every single day<br />Sending data across the network in a safe way<br />Protecting messages to make my pay<br />If you hack me, you’re guilty under DMCA</span></p><p style="margin: 0px 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 170%;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-style: italic;">Random numbers ain’t easy to produce…<br />Do it wrong, and your key I’ll deduce<br />RSA, only public cipher in the game<br />Creating it helped give Rivest his fame<br />If we could factor large composites in poly time,<br />We’d have enough money to not have to rhyme<br />Digesting messages with a hashing function<br />Using SHA1 or else it won’t cause disfunction</span></p><p style="margin: 0px 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 170%;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-style: italic;">[Chorus]<br />‘Cause I’m encrypting s**t like every single day<br />Sending data across the network in a safe way<br />Protecting messages to make my pay<br />If you hack me, you’re guilty under DMCA</span></p><p style="margin: 0px 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 170%;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-style: italic;">Password confirmed. Stand by…</span></p></blockquote><p style="margin: 0px 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 170%;"></p></span></div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
