<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: login | just some lazy admins]]></title>
  <link href="http://lazyadmin.me/blog/categories/login/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lazyadmin.me/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-13T14:25:01+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://lazyadmin.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thang Pham & Kao Nhan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's the difference between .bash_profile vs .bashrc]]></title>
    <link href="http://lazyadmin.me/blog/2014/08/13/whats-the-difference-between-bash-profile-vs-bashrc/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-13T14:19:15+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://lazyadmin.me/blog/2014/08/13/whats-the-difference-between-bash-profile-vs-bashrc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>.bash_profile is executed for login shells, while .bashrc is executed for interactive non-login shells. <br />
<strong>What is a login or non-login shell?</strong> <br /></p>

<p>When you login (type username and password) via console, either sitting at the machine, or remotely via ssh: <em>.bash_profile</em> is executed to configure your shell before the initial command prompt. <br />
But, if you’ve already logged into your machine and open a new terminal window (xterm) inside Gnome or KDE, then <em>.bashrc</em> is executed before the window command prompt. <em>.bashrc</em> is also run when you start a new bash instance by typing <em>/bin/bash</em> in a terminal. <br /></p>

<p><strong>Why two different files?</strong> <br /></p>

<p>Say, you’d like to print some lengthy diagnostic information about your machine each time you login (load average, memory usage, current users, etc). You only want to see it on login, so you only want to place this in your <em>.bash_profile</em>. If you put it in your .bashrc, you’d see it every time you open a new terminal window. <br /></p>

<p><strong>Recommendation</strong> <br /></p>

<p>Most of the time you don’t want to maintain two separate config files for login and non-login shells — when you set a <em>PATH</em>, you want it to apply to both. You can fix this by sourcing <em>.bashrc</em> from your <em>.bash_profile</em> file, then putting <em>PATH</em> and common settings in <em>.bashrc</em>. <br /></p>

<p>To do this, add the following lines to <em>.bash_profile</em>:</p>

<pre><code>
if [ -f ~/.bashrc ]; then
   source ~/.bashrc
fi
</code></pre>


<p>Now when you login to your machine from a console <em>.bashrc</em> will be called.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
